梁繼昌議員。
立法會主席。
to fill the vacancies.
which is unparalleled in other parts of the world.
extension of retirement age amendment bill，2019。
The supply and demand for judges are great.
The independent judiciary is a spine of our rule of law.
and this necessary entail enough good quality trained judiciary.
但係，有兩個因素，which would affect the attractiveness of the bench。
The reason why I say this place is unique because we have developed a bilingual judicial system.
Mr. President, I'm here to speak to give my support to the resumption of second reading of judicial officers.
As we all know, Hong Kong is a unique place to provide legal service to international business community.
now the supply of top quality common law judges is a problem in many common law jurisdictions, not just mentioning Hong Kong.
但係，也係事實，如果更多國際公司選擇香港法作為 govern law，和 govern jurisdiction。
Now I'm not just talking about this based on the fact that we are the prime arbitration centre for commercial disputes in Asia.
under Hong Kong courts, that would mean Hong Kong's legal business community and the professional services sector as a whole will benefit from this choice of law.
now in。
to be。
first of all。
和benefits。
或，Independence of the judiciary。
lucrative professional job to take on the bench.
Hong Kong's judiciary remain independent, but this, you know.
在過去22年，後的回歸主權到中國。
Some circumstances, this statutory retirement age could further be extended.
now，taking the two points I've mentioned about the prestige of joining the bench。
now one one of the very key component of good judiciary is independent.
這些 legal practitioners, many of whom are very experienced lawyers, who have given up a very
the prestige of the bench. Secondly, the benefits we are going to reward.
and the main crunch of this bill extends the retirement age of the high court judges, court of appeal judges and court of appeal judges and the final court of appeal judges to seventy, and in
Very good quality is coming to a lot of encroachments, especially when judges have been criticised in many media by key opinion leaders, politicians, columnists, etc. I think.
now of course this bill which extends among other things which extends the retirement age of the top court judges put us on par with the arrangements for many other common law jurisdictions including the United Kingdom, New Zealand and Australia.
has to be very low key.
now，having。
and in return for that.
We will have a very respectable.
and like most common law jurisdictions.
and prestigious judiciary，that is the key point.
他或她有個非常高的標準來 observe。
fix the benefits and tenure of the judges is one thing.
now normally speaking， the judges in this jurisdiction is， you know for life.
Now of course talking about benefits, that will include tenure of judges.
and to maintain the independence, integrity and the prestige of the bench is another.
A judge to be living this life. A judge leads a very low profile life.
not just not to make comments in public about current affairs, but his social life, personal life, family life.
now, most recently I've read a very alarming report prepared by the
The tenure of judges in Hong Kong are guaranteed lifelong, of course, unless the particular judge has committed a very serious, you know, misconduct.
Foreign Affairs Committee of House of Commons of the UK concerning British judges' British judges' role in Hong Kong's top court, and the headline is they are very concerned about the erosion or the perceived erosion of the one country two system.
has been handled by the government.
and， of course。
它意味著，equality。
Treatment of all people before the court.
從英國、澳洲和加拿大政府。
Of course, it also mean a system.
and which will lead to the actual or perceived.
and my understanding is that these common law jurisdictions.
now this is quite alarming, Mr President, as you know the committee has pointed out.
erosion of the one country two system and hence the independence of the judiciary.
and， the committee also further recommends that there should be a coordinated response.
It means accessible to independent legal representation at an affordable cost.
外務委員會的英國議會也非常關心關於最近的危機。
also supply the judges, the overseas non-permanent judges of our top court, the CFA.
The rule of law, as mentioned by my learned friend Regina Ip in this chamber, meant a lot of things. It means an independent judiciary.
The bench.
and the second more important point I have mentioned.
Too much protectionism to enter the profession.
of law which affords basic protection to human rights.
That once you become a judge, you cannot go back to private practice.
of judiciary to this city. One is the benefits and tenure of.
and it is a lifelong commitment, and you have to lead a very quiet life being a judge in the high court.
這些係核心價值， enlisted by the honourable Lord Bingham in his very famous book《The Rule of Law》，which I have read many times。
now there are two criticisms about the supply chain. I shouldn't say supply chain because it is a bit degrading. As a supply of good quality lawyers to fill the bench, mainly in this city, there are one.
now for example if you're a graduate of even you're a graduate of first class honour holder from Cambridge or Oxford when you come to practice or when you come to enrol the PCLL course in this city and only three universities here offer the PCL postgraduate certificate in law courses.
兩位講完，我覺得你離題啦，因為我哋唔係講緊PCLL嘅。我哋而家係而家係講緊二零一九年司法人員延展退休年齡嘅。請你翻返嚟呢個題目好嗎？哦，this piece of bill itself is not sufficient to deal with。
the the recent incidents of course have been quoted by many of my colleagues that it is a demonstration of the erosion of the rule of law, but I totally disagree with this point because these are incidents of breaking the law, but these are not incidents of breaking the rule of law.
嗱，我哋有好多議員咧，都。I'm not surprised that Mr. President, Mr. 我哋今次嘅辯論咧，就係講二零一九年司法人員。
延展退休年齡，我亦都係聽咗你係好耐咧，都係離開依個題目。請你翻翻嚟依個題目。Okay, the supply of the judiciary. I have talked about you know two points, which I think, Mr. President, you have totally missed my point because two points will increase the supply.
It's about integrity and and prestige of serving on the bench, which you have totally missed the point. And thirdly, now I come to increasing the supply of you know experienced lawyers joining the bench, which is more of a problem because as you know, and has also mentioned by my many learned friends.
still， you have to go through quite a ridiculous conversion course， and I have to say I have to declare my interest because my one of my children is pursuing a law degree and is becoming a lawyer soon。 but despite that fact that even a first class graduate from a first
the supply of the judiciary in this city, because merely extending the legal retirement age will solve the immediate problem, but not the long term problem of filling the judiciary, and we have to remove many of the artificial.
裁決。
遠離咗，請你翻翻嚟，亦都係收回你嘅指控。
如果你唔收為你嘅指控咧，我就會需要。
你係判決，我唔係問你判決，因為我係講緊我嘅法案，我話咗要增加供應嘅律師。因為你係指控我，請你收回你嘅。
子雄，I am saying the yesterday of your treatment on the tax concession bill and this bill is different. Is it an allegation? I do not think it's an allegation. I'm stating a fact。我現在暫停。
Protectionism to enter the legal profession. Okay, of course. I mean, I I think, Mr. President, you have using been using two yardsticks because as we remember, you have allowed people to speak on all subjects. 啊，梁繼昌議員，你係指控我。
係用兩把尺，係咪？請請你講，你係咪指控我係用兩把尺？我希望你收回依樣嘢。因為今日今日依個辯論咧，我係用同一把尺，我亦都係提醒你，你係。